In this lesson,
I use Expect Library to make test assertions,
and "deepFreeze" to make sure that
my code is free of mutations.
Let's say that
I want to implement a counter list application.
I would need to write a few functions
that operate on its state,
and its state is an array of JavaScript numbers
representing the individual counters.
The first function I want to write is called "addCounter",
and all it should do is to append a 0
at the end of the passed array.
At first, I use the array "push" method
to add a new item at the end of the array,
and it works.
However, we need to learn to avoid mutations in Redux,
and I'm enforcing this
by calling "deepFreeze" on the original array.
Now my attempt to "push" does not work.
It cannot add a new property to a frozen object.
Instead of "push", I'm going to use the "concat" method,
which does not modify the original array.
Now the tests pass without mutations,
and I can also use the new ES6 array spread operator
to write the same code in a more concise way.
My next function is called "removeCounter",
and it accepts two arguments,
an array of numbers,
and the index of the number to skip from the array.
So if I've got three numbers
and I'm passing 1 as the second argument,
I expect to receive an array with two numbers
with the second item skipped in the result array.
Usually, to delete an item from the array,
I would use the "splice" method.
However, splice is a mutation method,
so you can't use it in Redux.
I'm going to "deepFreeze" the array object,
and now I need to figure out a different way
to remove an item from the array without mutating it.
I'm using a method called "slice" here,
and it doesn't have anything to do with "splice".
It is not mutating,
and it gives me a part of the array
from some beginning to some end index.
So what I'm doing is that
I'm taking the parts before the index I want to skip
and after the index I want to skip,
and I concatenate them to get a new array.
Finally, instead of writing it as a method chain with "concat" calls,
I can use the ES6 array spread operator
to write it more concisely.
Now that we implemented adding and removing counters,
let's implement incrementing the counter.
The "incrementCounter" function takes your arguments,
the array and the index of the counter
that should be incremented,
so the return value has the same count of items,
but one of them is incremented.
Directly setting the array value at index works,
but this is a mutation.
So if we add a "deepFreeze" call,
it's not going to work anymore,
so how do we replace a single value in the array without mutating it?
It turns out the answer is really similar to how we remove an item.
We want to take the slice before the index,
concat it with a single item array with a new value,
and then concat it with the rest of the original array.
Finally, with the ES6 spread operator,
we can spread over the left part of the array,
specify the new item,
and then spread over the right part of the original array,
and this looks much nicer.
In this lesson,
you learned how to use the "concat" method
or the spread operator,
and the "slice" method
to add, remove, and change items in arrays without mutating them
and how to protect yourself with "deepFreeze" from mutation in your tests.